Macbeth Gallery Scrapbooks
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Macbeth Gallery scrapbooks
1892-1952
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
AAA.bowdnanc
Macbeth Gallery
3.3 linear feet
Macbeth Gallery scrapbooks date from 1892-1952 and provide almost comprehensive coverage of the gallery's history and day-to-day events at the gallery. Documented are many of the gallery's exhibitions as well as the fortieth, fiftieth and sixtieth anniversaries, and news of the art world in general. The scrapbooks contain exhibition catalogs, invitations, announcements, price lists, related news clippings, and some photographs. The scrapbooks form part of the larger Macbeth Gallery records.
Provenance
Described here are scrapbooks which form a part of the larger collection of the Macbeth Gallery records that were donated to the Archives in several installments between 1955 and 1966 by Robert G. McIntyre and Estate.
Separated Material
The scrapbooks form a part of the larger Macbeth Gallery records, also located at the Archives of American Art.
Related Material
The Macbeth Gallery records are available at the Archives of American Art. Macbeth Gallery exhibition catalogs are also held by the Frick Art Reference Library and the Watson Library of the Metropolitan Museum of Art.
Alternative Forms Available
The Macbeth Gallery scrapbooks were digitized in 2008 and are available via the Archives of American Art's website.
Restrictions on Access
The microfilm of the scrapbooks has been digitized and is available online via AAA's website. The original scrapbooks are closed to researchers due to their fragile condition.
Historical Note
The Macbeth Gallery was established in 1892 by William Macbeth, a Scotch-Irish immigrant who had spent ten years with the print dealer Frederick Keppel before he opened his doors to the art-buying public at 237 Fifth Avenue in New York. Despite the prevailing interest in foreign art at that time, particularly in that of the Barbizon and Dutch schools, Macbeth was determined to dedicate his gallery to "the permanent exhibition and sale of American pictures, both in oil and water colors."
Although some of the gallery's earliest exhibitions were of work by European artists, the business soon became the only gallery in continuous operation to keep American art permanently on display.
In 1908, Macbeth undertook what was to become the major event in the gallery's early history: the 1908 exhibition of "The Eight," featuring work by Arthur B. Davies, Willam J. Glackens, Robert Henri, Ernest Lawson, George Luks, Maurice Prendergast, Everett Shinn, and John Sloan. "The Eight" were an unlikely combination of social realists, visionaries and impressionists eager to challenge the dominating influence of the National Academy. The exhibition received an immense amount of publicity and instantly entered into art history as a successful assault on tradition. While the exhibition is reviewed in newspaper clippings contained in the scrapbooks, the exhibition catalog is notably missing from the collection.
The history of the Macbeth Gallery is a long and distinguished one with each successive proprietor making a significant contribution to art in America. William Macbeth helped establish an audience and a market for American art when few were willing to give it serious consideration. Robert Macbeth continued to cement the gallery's reputation as one of the leading firms in New York and was instrumental in organizing the American Art Dealers Association. Robert G. McIntyre claimed in a letter to Lloyd Goodrich, dated 22 June 1945, that the thing of which he was most proud was "the share I have had in the formation of the collection of the Addison Gallery of American Art, at Andover, Massacusetts." McIntyre was widely respected in the art community as a dealer, as an adviser to curators, and as a scholar whose research and book on Martin Johnson Heade helped "rediscover" an important American artist. Note: A more detailed history of the gallery is found in the finding aid for the Macbeth Gallery records in the Archives of American Art.
Scope and Content Note
Found here are twenty scrapbooks documenting Macbeth gallery's exhibitions and general history.
See index for List of Macbeth Gallery Exhibitions documented in the scrapbooks.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as one series:
Series 5: Scrapbooks, 1892-1952 (Box 120-130; 3.3 linear feet)
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Scrapbooks, 1892-1952, Series 5:; (Box 120-130; 3.3 linear feet)
  This series houses Macbeth Gallery scrapbooks which contain exhibition catalogs, announcements, invitations, price lists, related news clippings, and some photographs. The scrapbooks provide almost comprehensive coverage of the gallery's history and important exhibitions, as well as the fortieth, fiftieth and sixtieth anniversaries, and news of the art world in general. Many of the exhibition catalogs found here are annotated with prices and other notes. Although documented in news clippings found within the scrapbooks, the exhibition catalog for the gallery's 1908 exhibition of "The Eight" is notably missing from the collection.
  The scrapbooks are extremely fragile as the material found here is mounted on highly acidic paper and much of the material has come loose from the scrapbook pages. Consequently the original format of the scrapbooks is closed to researchers.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1892-1901 (Reel NMC1, Frame 269-424)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1893-1898 (Reel NMC1, Frame 425-449)
  - Scrapbook 3, 1902-1910 (Reel NMC1, Frame 1-268)
  - Scrapbook 4, 1907-1913 (Reel NMC4, Frame 1-110)
  - Scrapbook 5, 1910-1915 (Reel NMC2, Frame 1-266)
  - Scrapbook 6, March 1915-January 1918 (Reel NMC2, Frame 267-431)
  - Scrapbook 7, February 1918-January 1922 (Reel NMC2, Frame 432-668)
  - Scrapbook 8, January 1922-March 1923 (Reel NMC2, Frame 669-796)
  - Scrapbook 9, March 1923-December 1924 (Reel NMC3, Frame 1-98)
  - Scrapbook 10, January 1925-November 1927 (Reel NMC3, Frame 99-318)
  - Scrapbook 11, November 1927-June 1930 (Reel NMC3, Frame 319-516)
  - Scrapbook 12, September 1930-December 1932 (Reel NMc3, Frame 517-638)
  - Scrapbook 13, Fortieth Anniversary, 1932 (Reel Unfilmed, Frame Unfilmed)
  - Scrapbook 14, 1930-1934 (Reel NMC4, Frame 111-331)
  - Scrapbook 15, January 1933-February 1935 (Reel NMC3, Frame 639-767)
  - Scrapbook 16, February 1935-January 1938 (Reel NMC4, Frame 401-537)
  - Scrapbook 17, January 1938-July 1941 (Reel NMC4, Frame 538-671)
  - Scrapbook 18, July 1941-October 1945 (Reel NMC4, Frame 672-786)
  - Scrapbook 19, October 1945-November 1949 (Reel NMC4, Frame 787-899)
  - Scrapbook 20, 1949-1952 (Reel NMC4, Frame 332-400)
Index: List of Macbeth Gallery Exhibitions
This chronological list of Macbeth Gallery exhibitions is extensive, but incomplete. While an attempt has been made to establish the accuracy of the information provided here, dates and titles of exhibitions are not guaranteed to be accurate. Most of the exhibitions listed here are documented in the scrapbooks through exhibition catalogs and/or invitations, lists of artwork and news clippings. The list is annotated with AAA microfilm reel and frame numbers to assist researchers in locating material on specific exhibitions.
Scrapbook 1, 1892-1901
Date Exhibition
Dec. 7-21, 1892 Water Colors by American Artists (NMc1: 273-275)
Jan.23-Feb.11, 1893 Landscapes in Oil (NMc1: 276-277)
Feb. 27-Mar. 18, 1893 Landscapes in Oil by William Keith (NMc1: 278-279)
Mar. 20-Apr. 8, 1893 Watercolors by Dutch Artists (NMc1: 281-282)
Nov. 8-29, 1893 Second Annual Exhibition of Watercolors by American Artists (NMc1: 283-285)
Dec. 2-16, 1893 Drawings in Watercolors and in Black and White by C. R. Grant and Wilson De Meza (NMc1: 287-290)
Jan. 20-Feb. 3, 1894 Pictures and Sketches by Anton Mauve (NMc1: 291-292, 311-313)
Feb. 6-17, 1894 Paintings by Henry W. Ranger (NMc1: 295-296)
Feb. 23-Mar. 8, 1894 Paintings by Gaylord Langston Truesdel (NMc1: 299-300)
Mar. 16-29, 1894 Figure Subjects by Seven American Artists (NMc1: 302-303)
Apr. 13-May 6, 1894 Landscapes by American Artists (NMc1: 304-305)
Dec. 1-22, 1894 Paintings and Drawings by D.A.C. Artz (NMc1: 315-316)
Feb. 2-16, 1895 Paintings and Sketches by Theodore Robinson (NMc1: 318-319)
Mar. 15-30, 1895 Pictures and Sketches by Anton Mauve (NMc1: 321-323)
Feb. 17-29, 1896 Paintings in Oil by Philip Zilcken (NMc1: 329-330)
Mar. 9-21, 1896 Paintings by Arthur B. Davies (NMc1: 329-331)
Mar. 6-20, 1897 Paintings by Robert C. Minor (NMc1: 343-344)
Apr. 24-May 8, 1897 Paintings by Arthur B. Davies (NMc1: 348-349)
Jan. 17-29, 1898 Portrait Drawings in Pastel and Chalk by Sergeant Kendall (NMc1: 356-357)
Jan. 31-Feb. 12, 1898 Expressions of New England Landscape by Leonard Ochtman (NMc1-358-359)
Jan. 9, 1898 Exhibition of Pictures and Sketches by Anton Mauve (NMc1: 362)
Nov. 7, 1898 Exhibition of Watercolors by Mr. Ozawa of Tokyo, Japan (NMc1: 363)
Jan. 9-21, 1899 Paintings by Willbur A. Reaser (NMc1: 366-367)
Feb. 1-14, 1899 Paintings by H. M. Rosenberg (NMc1: 368-369)
Feb. 17-Mar. 9, 1899 Paintings by Charles Walter Stetson (NMc1: 370-371)
Jan. 8-20, 1900 Twenty-seven Drawings by Childe Hassam (NMc1: 376-377)
Mar. 9-24, 1900 Watercolors and Monotypes in Color by Maurice B. Prendergast (NMc1: 379-380)
Nov. 19-Dec. 1, 1900 Pictures by Rosina Emmet Sherwood (NMc1: 383-384)
Jan. 21-Feb. 2, 1901 Pictures and Portraits by Wilbur A. Reaser (NMc1: 385)
Feb. 25-Mar. 9, 1901 Frederick Ballard Williams (NMc1: 394-395)
Feb. 4-16, 1901 Landscapes by Alexander H. Wyant and George Inness (NMc1: 390-391)
May 9-31, 1901 Paintings by Arthur B. Davies (NMc1: 400-402)
Nov. 29-Dec. 14, 1901 Watercolors, Color Prints from Wood Blocks and Etchings Printed in Color by Helen Hyde (NMc1: 405-406)
Scrapbook 2, 1893-1898
Primarily news clippings.
Scrapbook 3, 1902-1910
Date Exhibition
Feb. 3-15, 1902 Private Collection of American Pictures (NMc1: 2-5)
Mar. 17-29, 1902 Some Phases of London When the Lamps Are Lighted, Done in Pastel by Fernand Lungren (NMc1: 10-13)
Mar. 31-Apr. 5, 1902 Group of Pictures by Sidney Starr (NMc1: 13)
Apr. 1-12, 1902 Pictures by Robert Henri (NMc1: 15-16)
Apr. 14-26, 1902 Drawings by Jane Erin Emmet (NMc1: 21-22)
Apr. 28-May 11, 1902 Landscapes by W. L. Lathrop (NMc1: 20)
Jan 19-31, 1903 Drawings and Sketches by Homer D. Martin, 1836-1897 (NMc1: 27)
Jan. 27-Feb. 11, 1905 Pictures by William Sartain (NMc1: 37-39)
Feb. 23-Mar. 8, 1905 Paintings by Arthur B. Davies (NMc1: 62-64)
May 1-6, 1905 Oil Paintings by American Artists from the Macbeth Gallery (at the Galleries of George D. Brodhead, Rochester, NY) (NMc1: 69-72)
Jan 29-Feb. 10, 1906 Abbot H. Thayer and Gladys Thayer (NMc1: 77-78)
Feb. 19-Mar. 3, 1906 Pictures by Charles H. Davis (NMc1: 79-80)
Mar. 10-24, 1906 Stephen Parrish (NMc1: 81-82)
Nov. 9-24, 1906 A Group of American Paintings (NMc1: 91-92)
Jan. 11-26, 1907 Paintings by William Sartain (NMc1: 100-101)
Feb. 1-16, 1907 Paintings by Paul Dougherty (NMc1: 105-106)
Feb. 23-Mar. 9, 1907 Paintings by Charles H. Davis (NMc1: 107-108)
Mar. 11-23, 1907 Portraits by Ellen Emmet (NMc1: 112-113)
Mar. 28-Apr. 3, 1907 Paintings by William Keith (NMc1: 115-117)
Nov. 11-23, 1907 Paintings by Augustus Vincent Tack (NMc1: 124-125)
Nov. 27-Dec. 12, 1907 Paintings by John La Farge (NMc1: 127-131)
Jan. 6-18, 1908 Paintings by Jerome Myers (NMc1: 133-134)
Jan. 20-Feb. 1, 1908 Paintings by Paul Dougherty (NMc1: 137-138)
Feb. 3-15, 1908 Exhibition of Paintings by Arthur B. Davies, William J. Glackens, Robert Henri, Ernest Lawson, George Luks, Maurice B. Prendergast, Everett Shinn, John Sloan (NMc:142-143 Catalog missing from scrapbook)
Feb. 19-Mar. 7. 1908 Forty Selected Paintings by Living American Artists (NMc1: 147-149)
Mar. 11-24, 1908 Paintings by a Group of American Artists (Deceased), Copley to Whistler (NMc1: 151-152)
1908 Kwaunon Meditating on Life by John La Farge (NMc1: 155)
Nov. 10-25, 1908 Paintings by Howard Pyle (NMc1: 158-159)
Nov. 27-Dec. 10, 1908 Paintings by Charles Melville Dewey (NMc1: 161-162)
Dec. 15-31, 1908 Bronzes by a Group of American Artists (NMc1: 165-166)
Jan. 7-21, 1909 Forty Selected Paintings by Living American Artists (NMc1: 168-169)
Jan. 22-Feb. 4, 1909 Paintings by Henry W. Ranger (NMc1: 171-172)
Feb. 5-18, 1909 Paintings by Paul Dougherty (NMc1: 176
Feb. 19-Mar. 4, 1909 Arthur B. Davies (NMc1: 178)
Mar. 5-Mar. 18, 1909 Paintings by Charles H. Davis, N.A. (NMc1: 183-184)
Mar. 19-Apr. 1, 1909 A Group of Figure Subjects by Blendon Campbell, Charles W. Hawthorne, Robert Henri, George Luks, Kenneth Miller (NMc1: 186-187)
Apr. 2-15, 1909 Paintings by Louis Loeb (NMc1: 188-189)
Apr. 16-29, 1909 Paintings by a Group of Boston Artists (NMc1: 191-192)
May 10-22, 1909 Paintings by American Artists from the Macbeth Galleries, New York [at Findlay Art Co., Kansas City, MO] (NMc1: 195-197)
Nov. 18-Dec. 4, 1909 Paintings by Albert P. Lucas (NMc1: 203-205)
Dec. 7-24, 1909 Watercolors and Pastels by American Artists (NMc1: 207-210)
Dec 7-24, 1909 Second Annual Exhibition of Bronzes by American Sculptors (NMc1: 211-212)
Jan. 6-19, 1910 Sixteen Paintings of the Cornish Coast by Paul Dougherty (NMc1: 213-215)
Jan. 20-Feb. 2, 1910 Paintings by Mary Curtis Richardson of San Francisco (NMc1: 218-220)
Jan. 20-Feb. 2, 1910 First Exhibition of Paintings by Ben Foster (NMc1: 216-218)
Feb 3-16, 1910 Landscapes and Figures by Frederick Ballard Williams (NMc1: 227-229)
Feb. 3-16, 1910 Spanish Paintings by F. Luis Mora (NMc1: 225-227)
Feb. 17-Mar. 2, 1910 The Fur Jacket by J. McNeill Whistler (NMc1: 231-232)
Feb. 17-Mar. 2, 1910 Paintings by William Sartain (NMc1: 233-235)
Mar. 3-16, 1910 Fourteen Landscapes by Charles H. Davis (NMc1: 237-239)
Mar. 3-16, 1910 Recent Portraits by Cecilia Beaux (NMc1: 239-240)
Mar. 17-30, 1910 Paintings by Hermann Dudley Murphy (NMc1: 244-246)
Mar. 17-30, 1910 Figure Paintings by Charles W. Hawthorne (NMc1: 242-244)
Mar. 31-Apr. 13, 1910 Paintings of Baily's Island by Frederick J. Waugh (NMc1: 249-251)
Mar. 31-Apr. 13, 1910 Nineteen Landscapes by Chaucey F. Ryder (NMc1: 247-249)
Apr. 14-27, 1910 George B. Luks (NMc1: 253-255)
Apr. 30-May 14, 1910 The Woman??s Art Club of New York, Exhibition of Works in Oil and Sculpture (NMc1: 259-262)
Scrapbook 4, 1907-1913
Primarily news clippings.
Scrapbook 5, 1910-1915
Date Exhibition
Nov. 3-16, 1910 Recent Paintings by Charles W. Hawthorne (NMc2: 1-2)
Nov. 17-30, 1910 The Navajo Country in Watercolors by Frederick J. McComas (NMc2: 4-6)
Dec. 6-24, 1910 Watercolors, Pastels and Small Bronzes (NMc2: 7-14)
Jan. 5-18, 1911 Portraits by Ellen Emmet (NMc2: 15-16)
Jan. 19-Feb. 1, 1911 Paintings by Henry B. Snell (NMc2: 17-24)
Feb. 2-22, 1911 A Group of Thirty Selected Paintings (NMc2: 25-28)
Feb. 23-Mar. 8, 1911 A Group of Forty Selected Paintings (NMc2: 29-32)
Mar. 9-22, 1911 Paintings by Charles H. Davis, Paul Dougherty, Daniel Garber, William Sartain, F. Ballard Williams (NMc2: 33-35)
Mar. 23-Apr. 5, 1911 A Group of Paintings by Ben Foster, Albert L. Groll, Leonard Ochtman, Chauncey F. Ryder, Gardner Symons (NMc2: 36-38)
Apr. 8-22, 1911 The Woman??s Art Club of New York, Exhibition of Works in Oil and Sculpture (NMc2: 39-42)
Nov. 16-29, 1911 Landscapes, Marines and Wood Interiors by Robert Henri (NMc2: 45-48)
Dec. 6-30, 1911 Small Bronzes by American Sculptors (NMc2: 49-52)
Jan. 3-16, 1912 Thirty Paintings by Thirty Artists (NMc2: 53-55)
Jan. 17-30, 1912 Paintings by Frederick C. Frieseke (NMc2: 56-58)
Jan. 31-Feb. 13, 1912 Paintings by Elihu Vedder (NMc2: 59-63)
Feb. 14-Mar. 2, 1912 Paintings by Charles H. Davis, Paul Dougherty, Ben Foster, William Sartain, Gardner Symons, F. Ballard Williams (NMc2: 64-66)
Mar. 4-16, 1912 Paintings by Emil Carlsen (NMc2: 67-69)
Mar. 6-19, 1912 Memorial Exhibition of a Collection of Paintings by Joseph R. Woodwell (NMc2: 71-75)
Mar. 18-30, 1912 Paintings by Arthur B. Davies (NMc2: 71, 76)
Apr. 1-10, 1912 Paintings by Richard E. Miller (NMc2: 77-79)
Apr. 15-27, 1912 A Group of Selected Paintings by American Artists (NMc2: 80-85)
Nov. 4-18, 1912 Frederick Ballard Williams (NMc2: 80-97)
Nov. 19-30, 1912 First Annual Exhibition of Painters of the Far West (NMc2: 99-103)
Dec. 3-16, 1912 Paintings by William Baxter Closson (NMc2: 99, 104)
Dec. 4-16, 1912 Marbles and Bronzes by Chester Beach (NMc2: 99, 105-114)
Dec. 30-Jan. 13, 1913 Lawrence Mazzanovich (NMc2: 116-119)
Jan 14-27, 1913 Paintings by Guy C. Wiggins (NMc2: 120-122)
Jan. 14-27, 1913 Paintings by Charles A. Hawthorne (NMc2: 120, 122-124)
Jan. 28-Feb. 10, 1913 Paintings by Paul Dougherty (NMc2: 125-127)
Feb. 11-24, 1913 Paintings by Gardner Symons (NMc2: 128-130)
Feb. 15-Mar. 1, 1913 Annual Exhibition of The Woman??s Artclub (NMc2: 131-136)
Feb. 25-Mar. 10, 1913 Paintings by F. C. Frieseke (NMc2: 137-138)
Mar. 4-17, 1913 Paintings by Charles Morris Young (NMc2: 137-142)
Mar. 11-24, 1913 Landscapes by F.K.M. Rehn, N.A. (NMc2: 143-147)
Mar. 18-31, 1913 Paintings by John Carlson (NMc2: 148-151)
Mar. 25-Apr. 7, 1913 A Selected Group of Paintings (NMc2: 148, 152-154)
Apr. 15-28, 1913 A Selected Group of American Paintings (NMc2: 155-158)
Apr. 15-28, 1913 Paintings and Pastels by Blendon R. Campbell (NMc2: 155, 159)
Oct. 14-27, 1913 Paintings by Katherine S. Dreier (NMc2: 161-163)
Oct. 28-Nov. 10, 1913 A Group of Selected Paintings by American Artists (NMc2: 164-166)
Nov. 17-24, 1913 Thirty Paintings by Thirty Artists (NMc2: 167-169)
Dec. 2-15, 1913 Second Exhibition by the Society of Men Who Paint the Far West (NMc2: 172-176)
Jan. 1914 Drawings of Game Birds by Frank W. Benson (NMc2: 179-180)
Jan. 6-19, 1914 Paintings by Emil Carlsen, Paul Dougherty, Frederick C. Frieseke, Childe Hassam, Willard L. Metcalf, Kenneth H. Miller, J. Alden Weir (NMc2: 179, 181-183)
Jan. 27-Feb. 16, 1914 Recent Sculpture by Chester Beach (NMc2: 185-186)
Jan. 27-Feb. 16, 1914 Paintings by Charles H. Davis, Daniel Garber, Richard E. Miller, Chauncey F. Ryder, Gardner Symons (NMc2: 185, 187)
Feb. 17-Mar. 2, 1914 Sculpture by Chester Beach, Abastenia St. L. Eberle, Mahonri Young (NMc2: 188-191)
Feb. 17-Mar. 9, 1914 A Group of Selected Paintings by American Artists (NMc2: 188, 192-193)
Mar. 10-30, 1914 Sketches in Passing by Frederick J. Waugh (NMc2: 195, 208-209)
Mar. 11-30, 1914 A Collection of Paintings by Deceased American Artists (NMc2: 195-207)
Mar. 31-Apr. 20, 1914 A Group of Selected Paintings by American Artists (NMc2: 212-217)
Apr. 21, 1914 A Group of Selected Paintings by American Artists (NMc2: 219-224)
Oct. 27-Nov. 16, 1914 A Group of Selected Paintings by American Artists (NMc2: 226-227)
Nov. 17-Dec. 7, 1914 Portrait Heads in Terra Cotta by Janet Scudder (NMc2: 233)
Nov. 17-Dec 7, 1914 Recent Paintings by Robert Henri (NMc2: 235-237)
Dec. 8-28, 1914 Exhibition of Home Pictures (NMc2: 243-247)
Jan. 5-25, 1915 A Group of Selected Paintings (NMc2: 243, 248-249)
Jan. 26-Feb. 15, 1915 Thirty Paintings by Thirty Artists (NMc2: 251-254)
Jan. 26-Feb. 15, 1915 Parisian Sketches by Lester D. Boronda (NMc2: 251)
Feb. 2-15, 1915 Our Untrodden Empire: A Collection of Paintings Executed in South Central Alaska by Robert V. Sewell (NMc2: 257-260)
Feb. 16-Mar. 8, 1915 Paintings by Deceased American Artists (NMc2: 262, 265)
Feb. 16-Mar. 8, 1915 Small Paintings by Guy C. Wiggins (NMc2: 261)
Feb. 16-Mar. 8, 1915 Paintings by Colin Campbell Cooper (NMc2: 261-264)
Scrapbook 6, March 1915-January 1918
Date Exhibition
Mar. 10-30, 1915 The Dance As Interpreted in Marble and Bronze by American Sculptors (NMc2: 267)
Mar. 30-Apr. 19, 1915 Paintings by Twelve Landscape Painters (NMc2: 274-277)
Sept. 27-Oct. 17, 1915 Paintings and Sculpture by Woman Artists for the Benefit of the Woman Suffrage Campaign (NMc2: 279-283)
Oct. 30-Nov. 19, 1915 Oils and Water Colors by Hayley Lever; Recent Paintings by Randall Davey (NMc2: 294-296
Dec. 4-31, 1915 Third Exhibition of the Society of Men Who Paint the Far West (NMc2: 300, 302-305)
Feb. 1916 Decorations by Elmer Mac Rae (NMc2: 318-319)
Jan. 4-18, 1916 Recent Paintings by F. C. Frieseke (NMc2: 306-307)
Jan. 4-18, 1916 Paintings by John F. Carlson (NMc2: 306, 309-310)
Jan. 19-Feb. 1, 1916 Paintings by Emil Carlsen, Helen M. Turner, Daniel Garber (NMc2: 313)
Jan. 19-Feb. 1, 1916 Decorative Panels of Flowers, Birds and Animals by F. S. Church (NMc2: 311,317)
Feb. 2-15, 1916 Paintings by Jules Guerin (NMc2: 318-321)
Feb. 16-29, 1916 Annual Exhibition of Thirty Paintings by Thirty Artists (NMc2: 323-326)
Mar. 1916 Group of High Fire Porcelains by Adelaid Alsop Robineau of Syracuse, NY, recently shown at the Panama-Pacific Exposition (NMc2: 322)
Mar. 8-21, 1916 Paintings by Charles H. Davis, Paul Dougherty, Kenneth H. Miller, Chauncey F. Ryder, William Sartain (NMc2: 329-330)
Mar. 22-Apr.4, 1916 Recent Water Colors by Charles Hovey Pepper (NMc2: 333)
Mar. 22-Apr. 4, 1916 Paintings, Drawings and Sculpture by Arthur B. Davies, Walt Kuhn, Jules Pascin (NMc2: 332, 334)
Apr. 6-27, 1916 Paintings by American Artists Past and Present (NMc2: 338-341)
Oct. 31-Nov. 13, 1916 The Whalers of New Bedford: Paintings by Clifford W. Ashley (NMc2: 346-348)
Oct. 31-Nov. 14, 1916 Special Exhibition by Painter Friends (NMc2: 346)
Nov. 14-27, 1916 Memorial Exhibition of Paintings by the Late Roger Donoho (NMc2: 349-353)
Nov. 28-Dec. 11, 1916 Paintings by Randall Davey (NMc2: 356-357)
Nov. 28-Dec. 11, 1916 Paintings by Kenneth Hayes-Miller, Benjamin D. Kopman and J. M. Block (NMc2: 356)
Dec. 13-Jan. 15, 1917 Watercolors by Paul Dougherty (NMc2: 358-362)
Jan. 16-Feb. 5, 1917 Thirty Paintings by Thirty Artists (NMc2: 366-368)
Feb. 8-26, 1917 Loan Exhibition of Paintings by Charles W. Hawthorne (NMc2: 370-379)
Feb. 27-Mar. 12, 1917 Paintings by Charles H. Davis, Richard E. Miller, Chauncey F. Ryder (NMc2: 381-382)
Mar. 13-26, 1917 Paintings by Arthur Crisp, Florence W. Gotthold, Martha Walter (NMc2: 384-385)
Mar. 28-Apr. 10, 1917 Pictures in Tempera of the St. Andrew??s Golf Links by William R. O??Donovan (NMc2: 386-387)
Summer, 1917 Summer Exhibition (NMc2: 388-391)
Oct. 1917 Opening Exhibition of Our Second Quarter-Century (NMc2: 393-396)
Nov. 3-17, 1917 Portraits by Louis Betts (NMc2: 400-403)
Nov. 13-26, 1917 Paintings by Arthur Crisp, Florence W. Gotthold, Martha Walter (NMc2: 384-385)
Nov. 22-Dec. 5, 1917 Paintings and Small Bronzes of New York (NMc2: 407-410)
Dec. 1917 Pastels by Lillian Crittenden (NMc2: 411)
Dec. 6-24, 1917 Small paintings and Pastels by Frederick C. Frieseke, Nancy M. Ferguson, Lilian Crittenden (NMc2: 411)
Jan. 2-31, 1918 In Aid of Men Blinded in Battle: Retrospective Loan Exhibition of Arthur B. Davies (NMc2: 412-416)
Scrapbook 7, February 1918-January 1922
Date Exhibition
Feb. 5-20, 1918 Watercolors by Gifford Beal (NMc2: 433-434)
Feb. 5-20, 1918 Intimate Paintings Moderately Priced (NMc2: 435-436)
Mar. 1918 Group of Paintings by American Artists (NMc2: 441-442)
Mar. 6-27, 1918 Thirty Paintings by Thirty Artists (NMc2: 438-439)
Mar. 27-Apr. 18, 1918 Paintings by Charles H. Davis, Ben Foster, Willard L. Metcalf (NMc2: 441, 443-444)
Apr. 18-May 10, 1918 Group of Paintings by Charlotte B. Coman (NMc2: 446)
Apr. 19-May 9, 1918 Paintings by Emil Carlsen, Childe Hassam, J. Alden Weir (NMc2: 446-447)
Oct. 23-Nov. 13, 1918 Opening Exhibition: Group of Selected Paintings (NMc2: 449-451)
Dec. 1918 Second Exhibition of Intimate Paintings (NMc2: 453-458)
Jan. 7-29, 1919 John H. Twachtman (NMc2: 460-470)
Jan. 27-Feb. 8, 1919 Paintings by Charles H. Davis and Paul Dougherty (NMc2: 473-474)
Feb. 17-Mar. 1, 1919 Thirty Paintings by Fifteen Artists (NMc2: 476-477)
Mar. 6-22, 1919 Paintings by Louis Ritman (NMc2: 480-483)
Mar. 6-29, 1919 Thirty Paintings by Thirty Artists (NMc2: 484-491)
Apr. 7-19, 1919 Paintings by Felicie Waldo Howell (NMc2: 496-497)
Apr. 7-19, 1919 Fifteen American Paintings (NMc2: 499-500)
May 1919 Comparative Exhibition of American Paintings (NMc2: 501-506)
Oct. 5-Nov. 8, 1919 Fifteen Paintings by Fifteen Artists (NMc2: 510-511)